-==www.RagBear.com==-
福尔摩斯探案集  第3季第6集
-==破烂熊乐园倾情奉献==-
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业用途
-=Keepfrds MNHD Team=-
校对: ptrpan
楼下有位绅士
There's a gentlemen downstairs...
让他等一会儿 哈德森夫人
Ask him to wait a moment, Mrs. Hudson.
他非常坚持
He's most insistent.
现在放松
Easy now.
放松
Easy.
我必须道歉
I must apologize.
我有点劳累过度了
I have been a little overwrought.
我是医生 先生
I'm a doctor, sir,
现在你必须放松
and I must insist that you relax yourself
在吃东西前先不要讲话
and say nothing until you have eaten.
谢谢
Thank you.
如果您给我点饼干和牛奶
If I might have a biscuit and a glass of milk
那样的话我一定会好些
I have no doubt I should soon be better.
哈德森夫人现在正准备吃的呢
Mrs. Hudson is preparing something at this moment.
拜托 请原谅我的衰弱
Please, please, please forgive this weakness.
我真的必须...
I really must...
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes.
听您吩咐
At your service.
文学硕士
Master of arts.
哲学博士
Doctor of Philosophy.
修道学校的校长
Principal of the Priory School.
哈克斯达堡博士 像您这样显贵的漂流者
Is it not everyday, Doctor Huxtable,
在我家炉前的地毯上遇难
that so distinguished a castaway as yourself
这可不是每天都有的事
is beached upon on the hearthrug.
为了猜测是什么风暴把您吹到这里
In speculating what storm had blown you here,
我擅自查看了您的个人物品
I took the liberty of searching your person,
希望您会原谅
I hope you will forgive me.
是的 当然可以
Oh yes, yes of course.
请坐
Please sit down.
您的表
Your watch.
以前的三十年里没出现一点瑕疵
Unblemished for at least thirty years,
然而今天早上却被刮花了
suddenly this morning scratched.
当您把这些硬币揣进背心口袋里时
When you thrust those coins,
在无意之中将其划破了
unthinkingly into your waistcoat pocket.
一生的严习被置于不顾
The stern habit of a lifetime trampled under foot.
这件事可能微不足道
A small occurrence perhaps
但值得思考
but own small think in a way
一根颤动的针
that a vibrating needle
可能就预示着一场地震
may signal an earthquake.
你脏乱的胡须表明
The state of your beard demonstrates
你的生活方式被明显打乱了
a considerable disruption to your routine.
在三天前?
Three days ago?
是的 先生
Yes sir.
福尔摩斯先生 我请求你与我一同
Mr. Holmes, I beg you to accompany me
立即北上前往麦克尔顿
north to Mackleton immediately.
这是极为重要的事情
A matter of the utmost importance.
恕难从命
Awe, I regret.
华生大夫和我
Doctor Watson and I
目前焦头烂额
are extremely pressed just at the moment.
我要处理费尔斯文件案
I'm retained in the case of the Ferrers Documents,
华生大夫还告诉我
and Doctor Watson tells me
他正为目前猩红热的流行
that he's run off his feet
忙得不可开交
by this recent epidemic of this Scarlet Fever.
而且阿巴加文尼
And then of course,
谋杀案马上就要开审了
there's Abergavenny murder coming off trial.
现在 唯有极其重要的案件
Now, only a very important issue
才能引起我们的注意
could call us away at the present.
重要的 先生?
Important, sir?
重要的案件?
Important?
请问您听说过
I dare say you've heard of
霍尔得芮斯公爵吗?
the Duke of Holdernesse?
前内阁大臣?
The former cabinet minister?
不仅如此 华生
More than that, Watson.
他名字背后的头衔
The letters after his name, huh,
可是数不胜数
almost half the alphabet.
国王最伟大的臣民之一
One of the greatest subjects of the crown,
是吗 哈克斯达堡博士?
hey Doctor Huxtable?
不但是最伟大的
One of the greatest and probably
而且还是最富有的人
one of the wealthiest.
容我骄傲地宣布 他也是我的邻居
He is also, I'm proud to say, in my neighbor.
霍尔得芮斯府 他的乡间住宅
Holdernesse Hall, his countryseat,
离修道院公学很近
is across from the valley from the Priory School.
公爵深居简出
Duke is an intensely solitary man.
他回避公众的视线
He appalls the prospect of public scrutiny
但在此事上 这也成了他焦虑的来源
but such is his anxiety in this matter
公爵大人已经准备好
that his grace is prepared to write a check
花五千英磅来掩人耳目
for five thousand pounds to see the business off
另一千英磅
and another thousand pounds
使坏人得到应有的惩罚
to see justice visited upon the villains.
事情就是如此重要
That is how important it is.
诱人的回报 哈克斯达堡博士
A princely offer, Doctor Huxtable.
但您并没有陈述案情
You have failed in describing villainy.
请原谅
Forgive me.
萨特尔勋爵 公爵的独子
Lord Saltire, the Duke's son, his only child,
被绑架了
has been abducted.
从修道公学里吗
From the Priory School?
是的
Yes.
在你的管护下?
When he was in your care?
不错
Quite.
此事就发生在三天前?
And this abduction happened three days ago?
上周六的晚上
Last Saturday night.
你为何过了这么久才来找我
Why have you waited so long before consulting me?
公爵大人担心
His Grace has a deep horror
这会把他的家庭不幸
of his family unhappiness
公之于众
being dragged before the world.
公爵要求警方
The police have been requested by the Duke
带着这种警戒行事 他们...
to proceed with such caution that they...
我明白了
I see.
事件处理得极为不妥当
This affair has been deplorably handled.
我不得不承认
I feel it and admit it.
索要多少赎金呢?
What form of the demand for ransom take?
没有
There has been none.
不要赎金?
No demand for ransom?
不要
None.
有一件事
It is one of the most
最为令人困惑
perplexing aspects of the business
那就是男孩并不是唯一失踪的人
for the boy was not alone in his flight.
德育教师赫尔・黑底格
Herr Heidegger, the German master,
也失踪了
is also missing,
顺便说一句 连同他的自行车
as indeed, by the way, is his bicycle.
如果是他绑架了男孩
If he has abducted the boy
为何没有接到索要赎金的要求呢
why has no demand for money been received?
黑底格是从瑞士来投奔我的
Heidegger came to me from Switzerland
对他的评价一向很好
with the very best references.
只有一辆自行车丢失吗
Was any other bicycle missing?
是的
Oh no.
你确定吗      确定
You're certain?        Right.
艾威灵先生检查过所有的自行车
Quite Mr. Aveling checked all the bicycles.
哈克斯达堡博士 你的意思是
Doctor Huxtable do you really mean to suggest
这个德语教师骑着自行车
that this German master rode off upon his bicycle
把男孩夹在腋下
in the dead of night
在黑夜出逃吗?
bearing the boy in his arms?
不是
No.
那你得出的是什么结论?
Then what is this theory in your mind?
自行车可能是个障眼法
The bicycle may have been a blind.
他可能把车藏在什么地方
He may have hidden it somewhere,
双双步行离开
and the pair gone off on foot.
当然他也可以藏上两辆自行车
Surely he would have hidden a couple of bicycles
如果他想造成这种假象的话
if he desired to give that impression.
我想是的
Yes I suppose he would.
当然他会 哈克斯达堡博士
Of course he would. Doctor Huxtable,
你的障眼法理论显然说不通
this blind theory of yours will not do.
但这也算是
It is an admirable starting point
一个调查的良好开端
for an investigation.
华生 你能马上叫辆马车吗
Watson, would you send for the cab immediately?
现在吗 福尔摩斯
Now Holmes?
叫车 收拾东西
Set, and pack.
我们刚好
We got just enough time
可以赶上从圣潘拉斯出发的午夜火车
to catch the overnight train from St Pancras.
哈克斯达堡博士 我将去你那里
Doctor Huxtable I shall do a little
做一点调查
work at your doors.
或许火车上不算太冷
Perhaps the train is not so cold
但像华生和我这样的两条老猎犬
but the two old hounds like Watson and myself
可能会嗅出点什么来的
make get a sniff on it.
我想萨特尔勋爵
I imagine the arrival
到你的学校就读
of Lord Saltire at your school
对你来说一定是无尚荣耀吧
must have been quite a feather in your cap.
是我最骄傲的时刻 福尔摩斯先生
My proudest moment, Mr. Holmes.
布莱克威尔发表
Ever since Blackwell's published
《哈克斯达堡对贺拉斯之管见》时
Huxtable's Sidelights on Horace,
在当时可是小有名气
a notable little success in his day.
你可能听说过      没有
You may have heard of it.        No.
那孩子有多大      九岁
How old is the boy?        Nine.
他入学多久了?
And he's been with you how long?
从冬季学期开始
Oh since the beginning of the winter term.
一个特别的孩子 他很快适应了学校生活
An unusual boy, he seemed to be fitting in well.
他 呃..
He um...
怎么了
Yes?
我正要说
I was about to say
他在家里过得不怎么开心
he was not entirely happy at home.
公爵的婚姻不算幸福
The Duke's marriage has not been a peaceful one.
去年双方协议分居
It ended in separation by mutual consent last year.
公爵夫人搬回了
The Duchess has returned
她父亲在威尼斯的府邸
to her father's palatso in Venice.
关于公爵的婚姻状况
This picture, of the Duke's marriage,
你是如何得知的?
how did you come by it?
这事人尽皆知吗?
Is it common knowledge?
我跟瓦尔德先生私下聊过几次
I've had some confidential talks with Mr. Wilder,
他是公爵的秘书
the Duke's secretary.
他提供了很多信息
He's been most helpful.
我想已经证实
And I suppose it has been established
那孩子并没有
that the boy has not returned
去意大利找他母亲吧
to his mother in Italy?
是的 已经证实了
Oh yes. Yes it has.
我无法告诉你 福尔摩斯先生
I cannot tell you, Mr. Holmes,
这对我是多大的心理安慰...
what a relief it is to me...
华生
Watson?
来了      您的饭 先生
Coming!        Your picnic, sir.
哈德森夫人 你怎么猜到的?
Mrs. Hudson, how did you guess?
经验而已 福尔摩斯先生
Experience, Mr. Holmes.
这意味着这两位先生可以在火车上
Well that means the two doctors can picnic away
边吃饭边讨论重要问题
to their hearts content on the train.
就算是我 可能都会发现
Even I may find my appetite
在充满乡土芳香的气氛中
is keener for a few days
胃口忽然变好了呢
in the bracing atmosphere of the peat country.
我想我可以公正地说
I think I will do myself no injustice
修道院公学是英格兰
when I say that the Priory School
最好的预备学校
is the most select preparatory school in England.
莱瓦斯托克伯爵
Lord Leverstoke,
布莱克沃特的伯爵
the Earl of Blackwater,
以及卡其卡特・索姆兹爵士
Sir Cathcart Soames,
他们都把自己的儿子托付给我
they all have entrusted their sons to me.
你从这儿是看不见霍尔德芮斯府的
You can't see Holdernesse Hall from here
但在礼拜堂塔上的视线是绝佳的
but there's a very fine view from the chapel tower.
这些遗址就不用看了
Heritage is skipping you.
我从那孩子的房间开始
I will begin with the boy's room.
他父亲写的?
From his father?
是他失踪那天早上送来的
It arrived on the morning of his disappearance.
他收到过从意大利来的信吗
Had he received one from Italy?
最近没有
Not recently.
信在哪儿
Where is the letter now?
找不着了
It cannot be found.
他被绑架时
It must have been on the boy's person
信一定在他身上
when he was abducted.
谁睡在隔壁房间?
Who sleeps in the adjoining room?
没什么大事 你们干你们的
It's alright. Just keep going.
我敢说你这孩子
I know this sort of chap I dare say.
睡觉遇到打雷也闹不醒
He could sleep through a thunderstorm.
我不这么认为 先生
I don't think he would sir.
真的吗 你为什么这么想?
Really and why is that do you suppose?
有只老鼠 先生
There's a mouse sir.
在壁板上 先生
In the wainscot, sir.
把我们俩都吵醒了 先生
And it wakes us both up sir.
这事时而会发生 先生
Sometimes sir.
老鼠?
Mouse?
那萨特尔勋爵房间有什么声音
So any noise from Lord Saltire's room...
门的响声 先生
Well the door creaks sir.
总会听到门响的
You always hear the door.
他失踪的那天晚上
On the night of the disappearance,
有听到什么异常吗?
did you hear anything then?
没有 先生
No sir.
甚至连哭声都没听到
You couldn't even hear the crying.
哭声?
Crying?
是的 先生
Yes sir.
他有时会哭 先生
He sometimes cries sir.
有时而已 先生
Sometimes sir.
谢谢你们
Thank you boys.
在地面上没有发现什么吗?
You have found nothing in the grounds?
我发现的东西都没很大用处
There's no knowing what I have found.
痕迹都被毁了
The trail is cold.
校长
Headmaster!
霍尔德芮斯公爵到了 校长
The Duke of Holdernesse is here headmaster.
谢谢 艾威灵先生
Thank you, Mr. Aveling.
和瓦尔德先生一起
With Mr. Wilder.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes?
是的
Yes.
公爵在等着呢 福尔摩斯先生
The Duke is waiting, Mr. Holmes.
怎么会没用呢
That will never do.
公爵大人
Your Grace,
瓦尔德先生
Mr. Wilder.
我昨天给你打电话了 哈克斯达堡博士
I called yesterday, Doctor Huxtable,
但要阻止你去伦敦
but I was too late
已经太晚了
to prevent your starting for London.
哈克斯达堡博士 公爵大人很惊讶
His Grace is surprised, Doctor Huxtable,
你在没有咨询他意见的情况下
that you should of invited Mr. Holmes
就擅自邀请福尔摩斯先生
to undertake an investigation
来进行调查
without consulting him first.
我想警察们没有进展
Well I thought that the police had failed.
没有确切证据表明
It is by no means certain
警察没有进展
that the police have failed.
不错 但说实话 瓦尔德先生
Yes, but surely, Mr. Wilder...
你一定很明白 哈克斯达堡博士
You're well aware, Doctor Huxtable,
公爵大人很焦虑
how anxious his Grace is
他极其想避免公众丑闻
to avoid all public scandal.
他希望在这件事情上
He prefers to take as few people as possible
知情的人越少越好
into his confidence.
抱歉 瓦尔德先生
I'm sorry, Mr. Wilder.
这很容易补救的
The matter is easily remedied
歇洛克・福尔摩斯先生可以
Mr. Sherlock Holmes can return to London
坐早晨的火车回伦敦
by the morning train.
不尽然
Hardly that.
我喜欢北部爽朗的空气
I enjoy your invigorating northern air.
无论如何 我都会
I shall spend, at any rate,
在您的旷野上度过几天
a few days upon your moors.
谁知道我会不会找到
Who knows I may at least find
赫尔・黑底格的自行车或者别的啥东西呢
Herr Heidegger's bicycle, if nothing else.
这可不是小事 福尔摩斯先生
This is not a trivial matter, Mr. Holmes.
我很高兴您能这么想 公爵大人
I am gratified that you think not, your Grace.
如果要说有什么意义 福尔摩斯先生
If there was meaning in that remark, Mr. Holmes,
恐怕我没有看出来
I'm afraid it escaped me.
您唯一的孩子失踪了
Your only child has disappeared.
您的希望 您的未来
Your hopes, your future,
您高贵的家族前程
your noble family itself
有断送的危险
is threatened with disillusion.
你想说什么 先生
Your point, sir?
我想问公爵大人
I ask your Grace,
什么才是本质
what is modesty to this,
您儿子的生命对家族更重要
to your child's life?
亦或是他的名声对家族更重要?
Or his reputation?
这个问题我暂时无法回答
Not then it might be replied
没有荣誉 还谈什么延续
what is continuance without honor?
然而我觉得你的话基本是正确的
However, I believe you are largely in the right,
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes.
如果你是指
If you refer to the constraints
我给警方活动所设下的约束
I have placed upon the activities of the police
或许我是有点强人所难
then perhaps I have imposed too much.
我有种病态的恐惧
I have a morbid fear
害怕公共的注意
of the public gaze.
如果我们不接受福尔摩斯先生的帮助
It would be foolish not to avail ourselves
那将是愚蠢的 詹姆斯
of Mr. Holmes' services, James,
何况他已经来了
now that he is here.
福尔摩斯先生
Mr. Holmes?
公爵大人
Your Grace?
或许你应该跟我们一起
Perhaps you would like to come and stay with us
住在霍尔德芮斯府
at Holdernesse Hall.
谢谢您 公爵大人
I thank your Grace,
但我想为了我的调查能顺利进行
but I think for the purposes of my investigation
我还是留在这奇案发生的现场
it would be wiser for me
要更加明智
to remain here at the scene of the mystery.
随你
As you wish.
瓦尔德先生或是我自己
Mr. Wilder or myself
会给你提供任何
will be available to provide you with
你可能需要的帮助
any assistance that you might require.
我能不能问问
Might I ask whether
对于你儿子的神秘失踪
you have formed any explanation
你想起什么起因没?
as to the mysterious disappearance of your son?
不 先生 没有
No, sir. I have not.
他是个好孩子 福尔摩斯先生
He is a fine boy, Mr. Holmes.
他到你班上多久了?
And how long has he been in your class?
从他到这儿开始
Since his arrival here.
关于他的家庭 他谈得多吗
Did he speak much of his family?
不多
Not much.
以我个人之见 他想念他母亲
It's my belief that he missed his mother
可能这与他父亲所作所为有关 你知道...
this is something of his father's doing, do you know...
关于公爵和公爵夫人的分居
The separation between the Duke and the Duchess,
他谈起过吗
did he talk about that?
不见得
Not really.
有点神秘 那孩子强调
It's a little mysterious. The boy insisted
他们两人互相深爱着彼此
that they loved each other very much.
你不认为不和的传闻
You don't soppose there'll be whistling
只是流言吗?
in the wind and all that?
不 他是个非常现实的孩子
No he is a very realistic child.
嗯 但不是个非常现实的家庭
Awe, but not a very realistic family.
有人告诉我 他们
I was told that they
曾经是地狱火俱乐部的成员
were once members of the Hellfire Club.
我想你应该不会知道
You wouldn't know, I suppose,
在失踪案的那天晚上
what time Herr Heidegger retired to his room
赫尔・黑底格是何时回房的吧
on the night of the disappearance?
不确切 但很晚了
Not really but quite late.
十一点之后
After eleven.
他是那晚的值班老师
He was duty round master that night.
我想他还骑自行车吧?
And a cyclists I believe?
是的 不错
Yes, oh yes.
萨特尔勋爵会不会骑车
Did Lord Saltire ever accompany him.
不 他还保持不了平衡
No he is not yet able to retain his balance.
我猜你应该不会碰巧知道
You wouldn't, I suppose,
黑底格的自行车轮胎
happen to know the make of tires
是什么牌子的吧
on Herr Heidegger's bicycle?
当然知道
Certainly.
布瑞门出产的 不错的自行车
A lovely bicycle by the way made in Bramen.
轮胎是帕默牌的
The tires were Palmer,
就是上面有条状花纹的那种
you know the ones with longitudinal tread.
这个我知道
I know the ones.
谢谢
Thank you.
太有用了
Doubly helpful.
我的荣幸 福尔摩斯先生
Pleasure, Mr. Holmes.
晚饭八点开始
Dinner will be at eight.
请原谅
I beg your pardon.
福尔摩斯
Holmes?
这个案子吸引住我了 华生
This case grows upon me, Watson.
有几点显然
There are decidedly points of interest
与此案有重大联系
in connection with it.
来看看这幅地图
Here look at this map.
可以肯定有些地点
There are certain geographical features,
与我们的调查
which may have a good deal to do
关系密切
with our investigation.
黑色方框是修道院公学
This dark square is the Priory School.
这个 大路在一英里之内
This, the main road with no side turning
是没有拐弯的
for a mile either way.
学校的北部
To the north of the school
地势缓缓升起
the land rises slowly.
南部
To the south,
一大块荒原
a large district of arable land,
有高墙和篱笆
with high walls and hedgerows,
骑自行车是不可能通过的
impossible territory for a bicycle.
你在奥卡堡有什么发现?
Oh what did you discover at Oakborn?
警察在那儿
Well the police had reports
做了全面的询问
from all over the place
是否看到一个男人跟一个男孩在一起
on a man and a boy seen together.
他们在今天清晨
They completed their investigation on the site
完成了这项调查
early this morning.
什么结果?      一无所获
What result?        Useless.
跟勋爵与德语教师的特征
None bore the slightest resemblance
没有丝毫相似
of the boy or the German master.
太好了
Excellent.
这些错误的观点
This mass of mistaken sightings, Watson,
证实了我的怀疑
it confirms my suspicion.
我想他们没走大路
I don't believe they used the road.
通往静谧之处的荒凉小径
That path of curiosity of quiet places
一定会带来发现的
will surely find the light.
我认为他们根本就没走大路
I don't think they used the road at all.
但自行车呢
But the bicycle?
骑车高手不一定非得在大路上才能骑
A good cyclist does not need a road, Watson.
荒原上小路错综复杂
The moor is intersected with paths.
我记得那时是满月
I remember the moons that were full.
但我们问题的答案
Now it is to the north
一定就藏在北方
that our quest must lie.
你做得很好 华生
You have done well, Watson.
快到晚饭时间了 很高兴吧
Dinner's soon, you'll be happy to hear
但还有一点
but I have do just have one point
我需要做一些调查
on which I need to be satisfied.
赫尔・黑底格的房间
Herr Heidegger's room.
就十分钟
Ten minutes.
福尔摩斯博士正在探寻
Doctor Holmes is being delving
霍尔德芮斯家庭的起源
into the origins of the Holdernesse family.
就像许多远古的线索
Like many ancient lines
来自一条肮脏的来源
it sprang from a very muddy source.
肮脏专家?
Muddy Doctor?
不用说得太详细了
Well not to be too delicate about it,
他们是盗牛贼
they were cattle thieves.
农民阶级 有胆有谋
A worrier class, ingenious,
但他们钱财的来源
daring but the basis of their wealth
却与别人家的牛休戚相关
was running off with other people's cows.
福尔摩斯甚至还告诉我 霍尔德芮斯
Holmes even tells me that Holdenesse has furnished
给地狱火俱乐部的疯子提供过资助
one of the madder members of the Hell Fire Club.
哈克斯达堡博士 怎么了
What is the matter Doctor Huxtable?
没什么
It is nothing.
但显然是有事的
But it's clearly something.
我的期望过高了
I expect too much I'm sure.
这是兼职
It is a part-time job.
说说你的期望吧
Tell us your expectations?
我不期望奇迹
I do not expect miracles.
我想我并不是一个
I think I am not a man
需要奇迹的人
who demands the miraculous...
但你还是什么都没发现
but you have discovered nothing.
我们一无所获
We haven't found,
从我们离开伦敦后一点证据也没发现
not a jot since the moment we left London.
虽然在事实上并不是这样
Although indeed that is not true.
你发现了两件事 但都微不足道
You have discovered two things, both falsums.
一个是一条无中生有的流言
One, a squalid piece of gossip
另一个就是关于我伟大赞助人家世的
and the other an epocriful and insulting fancy
无礼猜测
about the origins of my great patron.
我请你们来 福尔摩斯先生
I did not employ you to come here
并不是要给霍尔德芮斯的家庭蒙羞的
to blacken the name of the Holdernesses', Mr. Holmes.
冷静下来 哈克斯达堡博士
Calm yourself, Doctor Huxtable.
事实上 我们已经发现了一些线索
We have in fact, found some way,
我可以向你陈述一些细节
I can describe to you in some detail
是关于在那个戏剧性的夜晚
what took place in this school
学校里到底发生了什么
on that fateful night.
以及你那极其忠诚的
Also the behavior of your excellent
德语教师的作为
and faithful German master.
忠诚的黑底格吗?
Faithful, Heidegger?
是什么 先生
What sir?
赫尔・黑底格在十一点过后
Herr Heidegger retired to his room
回到了他的房间
soon after eleven o'clock.
他是那晚的值班人
He was the duty master that night.
现在我的朋友兼同事 华生大夫
Now my friend and colleague, Doctor Watson,
将重现当晚的情形
will impersonate.
黑底格还要工作两个小时
Heidegger has still two hours work ahead of him
他已经度过了劳累的一天
and it's been a long day.
他脱了外衣
He allows himself the comfort
让自己更舒服些
of removing his jacket.
他走到门边的箱柜
He moves across to the chest by the door
给自己倒了一杯雪莉酒
and pours himself a glass of sherry.
眼前的工作
Badly needed fortification
十分需要酒的支撑
of the task that lies ahead.
他拿起烛台
He collects the candle
将其放到桌上
and moves to his desk
还有22本作业要批
to correct twenty-two exercise books,
不仅包括语法练习
which contain not only Grammatik exercises
还有一篇冗长的作文
but also a lengthy composition.
我的观点是 哈克斯达堡博士
You see my point, Doctor Huxtable,
如果他没再干什么别的事的话
it would have been well after midnight
当他吹灭蜡烛时
if he had done nothing else,
应该是午夜过后了
when his candle fails him.
蜡烛放在门边的箱子里
The candles are kept in the chest by the door.
他起身想再拿一支
He arises from the desk to fetch another one
但没有光线 他找不到蜡烛
but he cannot see to find them,
所以他走到窗旁
so he turns to the windows
拉开窗帘
to draw the curtains
想借助月光看得更清楚点
to see better by the moonlight.
在门塔的屋顶上
Across the rooftops on the gate tower
男孩正在等待黑暗的到来
the boy has been waiting for darkness,
这样他的逃跑就不会被发现了
knowing that his flight must not be observed.
赫尔・黑底格看到了
Herr Heidegger watches
那孩子翻过墙
as the boy hurries across the ledge
去赴河边的约会
to keep his prearranged meeting by the river.
感到事态严重
Sensing the enormity of what was taking place,
黑底格跑向门口
Heidegger runs to the door,
就是这样碰倒了
knocking over what remains
他喝剩的那杯雪莉酒
of his glass sherry as he goes.
我明白了
I see.
谢谢
Thank you.
看来是我低估你了
It seems I misjudged you.
他做出去追赶孩子的这一决定
The wisdom of his choice
其理性是值得商榷的
to pursue the boy is questionable.
我相信他的命运由此扭转了
I believe his fate may be sealed.
请容我发问 福尔摩斯先生
You'll allow me, Mr. Holmes?
你的意思是?
Do you mean?
我希望不是这样 但如果我的推断没错
I hope not but if my reasoning is correct
那我真的为他担心
then I do fear for him.
那孩子呢?
And the boy?
哈克斯达堡博士 此案的关键
The key to that, Doctor Huxtable,
就在那儿
remains out there.
就在吉尔桥的另一边
Beyond the Drover's Bridge.
可怜的牲畜
Poor beast.
报喜鸟
Carrying crows.
他们名不符实
They ruin their name.
我们假设
So were assuming the boy
那孩子被绑上马背带走了
was taken away on horseback are we not?
不错
Certainly.
否则黑底格就不会
Otherwise Heidegger would not have
骑自行车来追赶他们了
needed a bicycle to pursue them.
但我们只能找到牛的脚印 福尔摩斯
But the only tracks we've found are cattle, Holmes.
福尔摩斯
Holmes?
痕迹 华生
A track, Watson!
有痕迹
A track.
自行车的?
A bicycle?
当然是某辆自行车的
Certainly a bicycle
但不是我们要找的那辆
but not the bicycle.
我很熟悉42种
I'm familiar with forty-two
轮胎留下的不同印迹
different impressions left by tires.
这是邓洛普牌的
This is a Dunlop
外胎是加厚的
with a patch upon the outer cover.
黑底格的车胎是帕默牌的
Heidegger's tires were Palmers,
这不是黑底格的车轮留下的痕迹
this is not Heidegger's track.
那是谁的?
Who's then?
到底是谁的?
Who's indeed?
华生
Watson!
这个是帕默牌的
These are Palmer tracks,
黑底格走过这条路
Heidegger has been this way.
绝对不寻常
Absolutely extraordinary.
邓洛普的车胎痕迹行驶过150码后
Dunlop tracks for a hundred fifty yards,
就消失了
they vanish
而帕默车胎很清楚地
and Palmer tracks quite clear
指向了这些岩石
leading to these rocks,
然后也消失了
they vanish too.
到处都没有马的痕迹
Not a sign of a horse anywhere.
华生 对于明显痕迹的发现
Watson, you have a blazing talent
你有惊人的天赋
for observing the obvious.
我应该带点午餐来的
I should have brought some luncheon.
到底赫尔・黑底格在追什么
Anyway what was Herr Heidegger cycling after,
牛吗?
cows?
按理说他们不会用牛背
Presumably they didn't abduct the child
来绑架那孩子
on the back of a cow.
马的痕迹被抹去了
All traces of horses obliterated.
证据显示
In much evidence the two bicycles
两辆自行车凭空消失了
have vanished into thin air.
这不可能
Impossible.
绝对不可能
Precisely.
我们不可能再犯早前的错误
It is impossible as we have mistaken it,
所以 在某个方面
therefore, in some respect,
我们一定是理解错了
we must have mistaken it wrong.
荒原边上更远一点
There's a hostelry mark
有旅店的标记
on the further edge of the moor.
福尔摩斯
Holmes,
彻斯特菲尔德路上有个旅店
there's a hostelry on the Chesterfield Road.
如果我们沿着这个方向走
Yes if he we keep on this line
我们就能到了
we should come up to it.
我得到那儿去碰碰运气
Well that's where I'm going to try my luck.
我饿了
I'm hungry.
福尔摩斯?
Holmes?
吃午饭
Lunch.
我亲爱的朋友 你一定饿扁了
Of course my dear fellow you must be starving.
现在看看地图
Now observe that map.
你会看到有家旅店
You will see that there's a hostelry
沿这个方向再走三英里
about three miles in this direction.
我们一会儿要见霍尔德芮斯公爵
We'll need some food if we're going to
我们得好好吃点东西
face the Duke of Holdernesse later.
没有发现吗?
Nothing?
没有发现
Nothing.
我必须告诉公爵大人
I must tell his Grace.
没有发现吗?
Nothing?
没有发现
Nothing.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
锁上了
It's locked.
这旅店就像这板上的画
Primitive but forceful
破旧却可憎
as sporting portraits go.
卢宾・黑斯先生?
Mr. Reuben Hayes?
你怎么知道我的名字?
How do you know my name?
门上印着的
It's printed over the door.
我们想吃点东西
We were looking for some refreshment.
是吗?
Were ya?
您能提供的话将不胜感激
And would be obliged if you could furnish it.
是吗?
Would ya?
会的
We would.
你得问问那女人
You must ask the woman.
可怜的人
Insufferable lout.
如果今天下午
If were going all the way
要去霍尔德芮斯府的话
to Holdernesse Hall this afternoon
我们可以雇几匹马
let us try to hire those unpreconditioned beasts.
你说什么?
What do you say?
要骑多远?
How far are you taking them?
从这到府邸一个来回
Just to the Hall and back.
您应该知道路程吧?
You know the way, I dare say?
我在那儿工作了十五年
I worked there for fifteen years.
好的 你们可以骑
Yeah, you can take them.
黑斯先生 你受伤了
My word, Mr. Hayes, you have injured yourself.
没事
It's nothin'.
我是医生 我确定你真的伤着了
I am a Doctor sir, and assure you it is.
你应该包扎一下
You should have it attended.
您怎么伤到的?
How did you come by it?
我的狗咬的
One of my dogs did it.
那些是抓伤
Those scratches.
是怎么回事
What about them?
粗看之下 伤痕之间离得很远
Well at a gentler glance they were that far apart.
什么动物能造成这样的抓伤呢
What animal would make such a scratch?
可能是公鸡中的战斗鸡
Probably a descendent of the champion jack.
斗鸡是法律明文禁止的
Cockfighting is forbidden by law
而且被禁了五十年了
and has been for fifty years.
法律禁止的东西可多了
Many things are forbidden by law.
在这样的地方哪有什么法律可言
What law is there in such places as these?
太棒了 黑斯夫人 谢谢你
Awe excellent, Mrs. Hayes, thank you.
你煮了什么?
What have you cooked?
血布丁 甜点和坚果
Blood pudding, sweets and nuts
怎么样 华生
How is it, Watson?
太恶心了 福尔摩斯
It is disgusting, Holmes.
那个女人
That woman,
她被什么东西吓坏了
she's frightened of something
或许不单是被她的丈夫
and more than that husband of hers.
诡计一环套一环
Deception upon deception.
但这一环环都是为了隐藏什么呢?
What was it intended to hide?
诡计?
Deception?
华生
Oh, Watson,
马蹄是跛的
my horse is lame.
太奇怪了
That's odd.
旧蹄铁 新掌钉
Old shoes, new nails.
先士们
Gentlemen.
公爵大人现在要见你们
His Grace will see you now.
瓦尔德先生
Awe, Mr. Wilder.
福尔摩斯先生 华生医生
Mr. Holmes, Doctor Watson,
欢迎来到霍尔德芮斯厅
welcome to Holdernesse Hall.
公爵大人一会儿就过来了
His Grace will be joining us shortly.
我们对您的推理绝技抱以厚望
We are placing high hopes on your skills Mr. Holmes.
您带来什么新闻了吗
Did you bring news?
只有一点
There is just one point
我还没搞清楚
in which I need to be satisfied.
是什么 福尔摩斯先生?
Yes Mr. Holmes?
这牵扯到公爵的个人隐私
It concerns the Duke's private concerns.
作为公爵大人的私人秘书
As his Grace's private secretary
也许我能帮上点忙
perhaps I can be of some assistance.
我知道在事情发生的那一天
I believe his Grace wrote to his son
公爵大人曾写信给他的儿子
upon the day this incident occurred.
不 那是在前一天写的
No I believe he wrote on the day before.
是的 但是他是那一天收到的
Yes but he would have received it upon that day.
是的 很有可能
Yes, quite probably.
那封信里会不会有什么东西
Might there have been anything in that letter
诱引那孩子逃跑呢
which would have prompted the boy to run away?
哦 我可不这么想
Oh, I hardly think so.
他能去的地方只有这里
Anyway he would have run here if anywhere.
也许他去意大利找她母亲呢?
Or to his mother in Italy?
不会 先生
No sir.
萨特尔勋爵肯定知道
Lord Saltire would realize
那样是不可能的
the impossibility of achieving such a goal.
即使是被那个德国人教唆
Even if abetted by this German,
他可是个聪明实际的孩子
he is an intelligent and practical child.
但他睡觉时也会哭泣
And yet he cries in his sleep.
公爵大人是自己寄的信吗
Did his Grace post the letter himself?
公爵大人可没有寄信的习惯
His Grace is not in the habit of posting letters.
那封信和其他信件一起
The letter was laid with others
放在书桌上
upon the study table
是我亲自放在那儿的
and I, myself, put them there.
除我以外能接触到它们的人
The only other person who would handle them
就只有瑞瓦兹了
would be Rivers,
他送日报到学校门房
who delivers the Daily Post to the lodge.
你确定这封信跟它们在一起
And you're sure this letter was among them?
是的 我能肯定
Oh yes. I observed it.
你发现什么了 福尔摩斯先生
And what have you observed, Mr. Holmes?
你的调查有进展了吗
How does your investigation progress?
你会让我失望吗
Are you to disappoint me?
我仍希望能带给您最大的希望
I hope still to render your greater happier
并使我自己成为更富裕的人
and myself a richer man.
你发现了什么?
And what have you discovered?
我澄清了一件事
It is mostly a matter of clarification.
我相信那孩子是
My belief is that the boy was
被事先安排好的诱饵引出了学校
tempted out of the school by a prearrangement
而我怀疑 他的母亲
and I suspect that his mother
可能正是诱饵
may have been the bait.
德语教师发现了他的出逃
The German master observed his departure
出发去追
and set off in pursuit.
我们在荒原上费了一番周折
We tracked the passage of his bicycle
追踪到了他的自行车踪迹
across the moors with much difficulty.
车胎印就好像
It is almost as if the tracks
被人有意擦拭过一样
were deliberately sponged by someone...
福尔摩斯先生?
Mr. Holmes?
有人驾着马车
Someone driving cattle.
你不会碰巧知道荒原上的马车...
You don't happen to know if the cattle on the moor...
它们怎么了?
What about them?
我希望你没有看见
I hope you have seen none.
在这种高地气候下
We cannot winter cattle outside
冬天我们是不驾车外出的
in our upland climate.
在接下来的这两周里
They will not be out of the yard for,
它们是不会再外出的
oh at least another two weeks.
那我还真是闭目塞听了
Then I've been as blind as the beetle.
谢谢你 公爵大人
I thank you, Grace.
旧蹄铁新掌钉 旧蹄铁新掌钉
Old shoes and new nails! Old shoes and new nails!
福尔摩斯 你应该来看看这个
Holmes there's something you should see!
一头牛如此行走奔跑可不寻常
It is a remarkable cow which walks, canters, and gallops.
看到这些马蹄铁了吗
Do you see those horseshoes?
看到了
I saw them.
带走霍尔德芮斯勋爵的人
Whoever took Lord Holdernesse
给他的马钉了不同的马蹄铁
Shoed their horses with different horseshoes.
以避免被人发现
To escape detection.
卢宾・黑斯是利用了
Reuben Hayes took advantage of
当地的历史
a piece of local history?
太糟了 华生 太糟了
It's bad Watson, bad.
北边的秃鹰为我们指明了犯罪现场
Those vultures of the north mark the spot.
德语教师
German master.
从尸体上能看出些什么?
What's left of him?
你好
Hello!
Hello, hello!
血肉模糊
Skin and blood.
用显微镜才能知道是不是人干的
Only a microscope would tell if it's human.
肯定与黑斯脖子上的抓痕相吻合
A consistent no doubt to the scratch on Hayes' neck.
是的
Oh yes.
死因呢
Cause of death?
勒杀
Strangulation.
喉头被重压
The larynx is quite crushed.
那个牧羊人
That shepherd can be
可以帮我们将这噩耗
our messenger to the priory school
传到修道院公学
with the news of this tragedy.
我们得靠走的了 华生
We must proceed on foot, Watson.
我曾很暖和
I was warm!
在那小旅馆里
At that Inn,
就像孩子们说的 很暖
warm as the children say.
我越是远离小路
The trail grows colder
我就越是寒冷
every step I take away from it.
我怎么知道把尸体放到哪里
How was I supposed to know where to put the body.
现在都结束了 阿瑟
It's all over now, Arthur.
卢宾・黑斯
Reuben Hayes.
但愿我们还不算太晚
Let's hope we're not too late.
邓洛普牌的外部加厚的车胎
A Dunlop with a patch on the outer cover.
这儿发生什么了 黑斯夫人
What happened here Mrs. Hayes?
我很高兴
I'm satisfied that you
你并不赞同对这桩买卖
have no liking for this business
并在他们的威逼下进行了反抗
and that you acted under coercion.
有人带走了那孩子
Someone came for the boy.
是公爵的秘书 瓦尔德先生吗?
The Duke's secretary, Mr. Wilder?
他们朝哪走了?
Which way did they go?
是穿过荒原跑了吗?
Across the moor?
沿着彻斯特菲尔德路
It's aboard the Chesterfield Road
往他的小别墅跑去了
where be his cottage.
谢谢 黑斯夫人
Excellent Mrs. Hayes.
我必须得去警告公爵 华生
I must alert the Duke's household, Watson.
你现在是那孩子的守护天使
You are now the boy's guardian angel.
我想公爵大人的支票簿就在桌子底下吧
I fancy I see your Grace's checkbook upon your desk.
我将很高兴看到您写一张
I would be glad if you would make me out a check
金额为6000磅的支票给我
for six thousand pounds.
最好您再背签下
Perhaps it would be best if you were to cross it.
我的代理银行是城乡银行
The Capital and Counties Bank,
牛津街支行
Oxford Street branch, are my agents.
福尔摩斯先生
I do not possess a temperament,
我可没有这种闲情
Mr. Holmes that appreciates
来欣赏将您那所谓的
the kind of acidulous pleasantry
尖酸的幽默
that clearly amuses you.
抱歉 但我可看不出来
I am sorry, but I do not see how
詹姆斯 就是瓦尔德先生
James, Mr. Wilder
会牵涉到这件事中
could possibly be implicated in this business
而且您也没有证据
and you average not proof of it.
不 我有证据
But I possess the proof.
这是毋庸置疑的
It is beyond debate.
你窗扉上的马蹄铁
The mud is scarcely dry on the
泥引还没全干呢
cloven horseshoes in your casements.
你为什么不相信我的话?
Why do you doubt my word?
你似乎对一切都闭目塞听
You seem to suffer from a blindness.
你这种做法会带你走向疯狂
Your own interest, which borders on madness.
公爵大人
Your Grace,
大厅里的画像
those portraits in the hall
是年轻时的你和你父亲
of you and your father as young men,
你的家庭秘密已经无法掩盖了
there your family liniments are very clear.
瓦尔德先生
How long has Mr. Wilder
为你效力已经多久了
been in your service?
你什么意思
What is your meaning?
你怎么敢 先生!
How dare you sir!
你根本不明白
You do not understand!
你是个无礼的人
You are a barbarian!
你永远不会...请立刻离开
You will never... please leave me immediately.
我不会...我
I won't...I...
如我所料
Then it is as I suspected
詹姆斯・瓦尔德先生是你的儿子
Mr. James Wilder is your son.
当我还年轻的时候 福尔摩斯先生
When I was a very young man, Mr. Holmes,
我也曾爱过
I loved,
爱之深
with such a love
一生唯有一次
that comes only once in a lifetime.
我想跟她结婚
I offered the lady marriage
但她拒绝了
but she refused it
因为那样的结合
on the grounds that such a match
可能会毁了我的事业
might mar my career.
如果她还活着
Had she lived,
我绝对不会跟别人结婚的
I would certainly never had married anyone else
但她死了
but she died
只留下一个孩子
and left with one child,
就是詹姆斯 因为对她的爱
James, whom for her sake
我抚养和培育这个孩子
I have tended and cared for.
我不能向世人承认我们的父子关系
I could not acknowledge paternity to the world
但除此之外
but in all other ways
我一直以亲生儿子待他
I have treated him like my son.
他要求过
He has required,
但他不断辜负了
but not warranted,
我对他的原谅
a father's forgiveness many times
对此我也原谅他了
and I have forgiven.
我原谅他
I have forgiven.
我一再原谅他
I have forgiven much.
公爵大人 对瓦尔德先生来说
Awe your Grace you have done all you can
您已经尽力了
for Mr. Wilder.
你必须意识到你已经失去他了
You must realize that he is lost to you.
他蓄谋绑架萨特尔勋爵
He's conspired to abduct Lord Saltire.
他是一起谋杀案的帮凶
He's an accessory to a murder,
不管他是否知情
however unwittingly.
在他犯下一桩
He must be found
更严重的案子前 我们必须找到他
before he's attempted to a crime even more terrible.
在你失去
He must be found
你倾力照顾的儿子之前
before you loose the son
我们必须找到他
that is left to you.
瑞瓦兹?
Rivers?
你负责搜查荒原
You are to organize a search of the moor.
沿着西边的森林
West Woods in a line
从寺庙到凉亭一路搜查
from the temple to the pavilion.
要让你的人
You are to employ the entire staff
全部出动
without exception.
你要找的是我的儿子 萨特尔勋爵
You are looking for my son, Lord Saltire.
如果你找到了瓦尔德先生
If you find Mr. Wilder,
请务必扣留他
please see that he is detained
并将他带给我
and brought to me.
瓦尔德截下了你的信
Wilder intercepted your letter
并在里面塞了一张纸条
and substituted a note,
由此诱导你儿子相信
which deceived your son into believing
他要见到他母亲了
that he was to see his mother.
凶狠的黑斯就是他的雇佣帮凶
The murderous Hayes was his paid accomplice
但警察都已被告知
but the police have been alerted.
黑斯跑不了的
Hayes will not escape.
华生?
Watson?
我把他们引到荒原上了
I tracked them over to the moor
可他们不见了
but they disappeared.
我把附近都搜过了
I searched the area
但他们就像用了遁地术凭空消失了
but it's as if the earth just swallowed them up.
根据我对你家世的调查
With my research into your family history
我似乎听到过
I've seemed to recall mention
有一个巨大的石灰石洞穴
of a huge limestone cavern
那里关着偷来的牛
where the stolen cattle were penned.
去大教堂
The cathedral.
快点
Come on.
Come on!
把他交过来
Hand him over?
不
No!
你得不到他
You shall not have him!
父亲
Father!
父亲 过来
Come Father!
父亲
Father!
詹姆斯
James!
我打算好好去爱弗朗西丝卡
I was disposed to love Francesca
不再是少年的激情
and not with a boy's passion
而是男人的真爱
but with a man's love.
我与她的婚姻
My marriage to her
被詹姆斯所嫉妒
founded on James' jealousy.
只要我还能在他身上
As long as I could see
看到他母亲的容貌和风度
his mother's face and manner in him
詹姆斯就知道他能阻挡
James knew he could keep me
我本该给我妻子的爱
from the love I owed my wife.
就算他对阿瑟很残暴
Even his cruelty to Arthur
我还是无法就这样放弃他
I could not send him away even for that.
所以我就把阿瑟送走了
So I sent Arthur away instead.
通过绑架他的弟弟
What did he hope to achieve
他想达到什么目的呢
by kidnapping his brother?
钱吗?
Money?
还是身份?
Legitimacy?
还有权力
And power.
在我之上的权力
Power over me.
他喜欢对我发号施令
He delighted in exercising power over me,
因为我们都否定他的权力
for me and you were to have denied him power.
你是否怀疑他就是绑架事件的幕后黑手?
But you suspected that he was behind the abduction?
是的 那是我最黑暗的时刻
In my darkest moments, yes.
但我仍希望能
Yet somehow I hoped to
救他
save him.
这看起来就像是漫长的忏悔
Well, a long penance it had seemed.
我只能希望
I can only hope that
弗朗西斯卡能原谅我
Francesca will forgive me.
谢谢你 福尔摩斯先生
Thank you, Mr. Holmes.
公爵大人?
Your Grace?
这是巨额酬金
This is a king's ransom.
你又为我带回了未来
You have given me back my future.
破烂熊字幕组
-==http://www.ragbear.com==-
欢迎加入